Finding Aid for John Engler Papers, 1968-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gubernatorial Papers, 1970-2003; 411 linear feet
  - Communications Division, 1991-2002; 99 linear feet
    - Speeches, 1991-2002; 21.5 linear feet
      - Republican Convention "Making Michigan #1: There's No Stopping Now!", August 27, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Gubernatorial Campaign Booklet "Making Michigan #1: Continuing Our Mission of Change and Reform,", September 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Department of Corrections Report on Ryan Prisoners' Escape; State Fair Governor's Day; Chrysler Cirrus Launch; Aetna Industries/ISO 9000 Proclamation, September 1-9, 1994 (Box 122)
      - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Rwandan Relief Effort, Selfridge ANGB, September 9, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Grand Rapids Economic Club on Crime, September 12, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Vining Road Interchange; Prisoners of War/Missing in Action (POW/MIA) Vigil, Novi; Michigan Jobs Team Partners' Conference; Keykert USA Cornerstone; Judge Daniel Ryan Investiture, September 16-20, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Sheriffs' Endorsement; Prosecutors' Endorsement; Patrick and Kathy Urbin Endorsement; United We Stand Rally, September 19-23, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Don Sundquist "Road to Victory" dinner, Tennessee, September 23, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Welfare Saving press conference; General Motors Executives' breakfast; Foundations for Justice/Supporting Crime Victims; Welfare Waivers/Reforms press conference, September 23-29, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Spence Abraham Gala; Linda Clark (Police widows) Endorsement; Michigan Bias Crime Response Task Force; Civil Rights Unity Dinner, September 26-30, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Plymouth Rotary luncheon, September 30, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Undated Campaign speeches, Fall 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: St. James' Roman Catholic Church 75th Anniversary, Ferndale; Polish American Congress 50th; Budget Surplus Press Conference; Economic Club of Detroit luncheon, October 2-3, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Council of Black Pastors of Detroit & Vicinity, October 4, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Pension Tax Cut Press Conference; University of Michigan Dearborn Groundbreaking; Ludington Pumped Storage Plant Settlement; Rock Financial Tax Cut Contest; Domestic Violence Summit; Senator Mat Dunaskiss Fundraiser, October 4-6, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Ford Pancakes & Politics event; Michigan Municipal League; ACCESS Community Center; Islamic Association of Greater Detroit, October 7, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Jewish Federation of Metro Detroit; Jackson Business Leaders; Sportsmen for Engler; Debate rebuttal; Right to Life Lifespan Breakfast; Highland Township Senior Center dinner, October 17-22, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Right to Life Benefit; Triple W Plastics opening; Upjohn dedication; St. George Orthodox Church dedication; Bosnian Unity dinner; Oak Park Tiute dinner; Spicer Engineering 50th Anniversary, October 20-25, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Form-Tech Steel Company Retention and Expansion; Metro-South Michigan State Police Post dedication; Monroe County Chamber of Commerce Koffee Klub; Kent County Fall Dinner; Haggerty Road Connector; Warren Senior Citizens Advisory Council; "Michigan is Open for Business;" Islamic Institute of Knowledge fundraiser, October 26-30, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Fenton Community Center Luncheon, November 1, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: Detroit Edison Pancakes & Politics; Groundbreaking for Shiawassee River Walk; X-Rite New Product Unveiling; Clawson Rotary luncheon; Michigan Livestock Exchange press conference; Michigan Chronicle Endorsement; Introduction Sen. Dole; Islamic Center of America dinner, November 2-6, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Election Night Remarks, November 8, 1994 (Box 122)
      - Remarks: ALEC Luncheon, Washington, DC; Welcome to Cardinal Maida, December 8, 1994 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Farmland Task Force; Secchia Report: "Toward User-Friendly Government;" Charter Schools bill signing (SB 896), December 14-21, 1994 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Michigan Jobs Commission becomes Department; GOP House Conference, Washington, DC, December 16, 1994 (Box 123)
      - 2nd Inaugural: "Michigan's Renaissance: America's Hope,", January 2, 1995; 2 folders (Box 123)
      - Economic Club of Detroit, January 10, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: House Testimony on Welfare Reform; Op Ed pieces, January 13, 1995 (Box 123)
      - State of the State: "Building on Michigan's Renaissance,", January 17, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Red Cross National Testing Lab dedication, January 25, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Prayer for National Leaders DC Prayer Breakfast; 94FY Books Closing Press Conference, February 2-3, 1995 (Box 123)
      - US House Testimony: Nutrition & Food Stamps/Block Grants and Clean Air Act Amendments, February 9, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Engineering Society of Detroit; Senate Budget Committee Testimony "Restructuring State/Federal Relationship,', February 1995 (Box 123)
      - Polyconomics Conference, BocaRaton, Florida, March 3, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Cato Institute Remarks, DC, March 14, 1995 (Box 123)
      - "No Devil in Devolution" Acton Institute Address, March 29, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Center for Strategic & International Studies, Advisory Board Meeting, DC, March 29, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Oakland Business Roundtable, April 7, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Merle Academy for the Arts Charter School dedication; Video Script/Rosa Parks' life; Celebrate America -- 100 Days (Atlanta); Meijer Gardens opening, Grand Rapids, April 7-20, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: House Republican Spring Dinner; Greater Thumb GOP Rally; Republican National Convention State Chairman's Meeting, April 25-28, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Ashbrook Center address (Ohio), May 1, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: May Talking Points; Welcome to President Bill Clinton at Michigan State University; St. Clair Community College; Tax Cuts #12-15 Press Conference; Capitol book press announcement; Art Van expansion; Novi Police Memorial, May 1-15, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Harvard School of Education forum, May 3, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Congressional Retreat address; Republican Governors' Association dinner (New Jersey); Dick Headlee Retirement roast, May 4-12, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Toronto Luncheon; IDRC dinner; Tulip Time; Richmond Police Bldg. Dedication; The Event (Developmental Disabilities Council), May 16-23, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Hoover Institute Talking Points: Revitalizing Federalism; Republican Governors' Association (Los Angeles); Republican Governors' Association dinner (San Francisco), May 24-25, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: June Talking Points; Reconciliation Breakfast; House Commerce Committee Testimony; Hungarian Prime Minister welcome; Amway Sales Convention; Grand Prix, Belle Isle, January 1-11, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Greater Detroit Chamber of Commerce Mackinac Island Conference, June 3, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Accident Fund Privatization; American Axle Open House; DSS Caseload below 200,000, June 20-22, 1995 (Box 123)
      - School-to-Work Conference, June 22, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Camp Grayling Review; '94 Infant Mortality News Conference; Frederick Douglass Dinner talking points; Vern Davis Anthony Farewell; Kids & Alcohol Press Conference; Michigan Information Network, June 23-30, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Statement on Gambling Decision, June 27, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Michigan Chapter International Council of Shopping Centers Annual Expo, Dearborn, June 28, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Grand Traverse County Governor's Breakfast; AD Smith MEGA Announcement; Prosecuting Attorneys' Association of Michigan, Mackinac Conference, July 15-27, 1995 (Box 123)
      - George Romney Funeral, July 31, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Ionia Fair; Michigan Companies in Japan, Tokyo; Upper Peninsula events; Lt. Gov. Conference Keynote; Michigan State Fair; Governors' Lunch at Fair, August 2, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Triplets' First Bridgewalk; Lansing Community College Groundbreaking; Max Fisher tribute; Washtenaw County House GOP Golf fundraiser; New York Republican Governors' Association Dinner, September 4-13, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Policy Exchange Foundation Remarks on Welfare, "No Devil in Devolution,", September 8, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Governors Michigan Association of School Boards Education Summit, September 19, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: Michigan Top 10 Businesses; Newcomen Society Dinner; BASF Waterfront Park, Wyandotte Golf Course dedication; National Rubber Co. Groundbreaking, September 20-25, 1995 (Box 123)
      - State Bar Keynote Address, September 21, 1995 (Box 123)
      - Remarks: House GOP Fundraiser/Lansing; Spence Abraham Introduction, Republican Leadership Conference Intro. Newt Gingrich; Republican Governors' Association New England forum, September 21-26, 1995 (Box 123)
      - First Russell Kirk Memorial Lecture Heritage Foundation, DC, September 26, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Citizens' Research Council; 1995 Exporter of the Year dinner, September 28, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Hon. Robert P. Young Investiture; Mead Johnson opening; Livingston Trade Academy; Cass Tech Award; Father-Son Breakfast, Detroit County Day; Behr Systems Plant Dedication; Griffin Portrait Ceremony; Michigan State University Homecoming, October 6, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Detroit Clergy Summit Wayne State, October 17, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Old Kent Bank Luncheon; Cabinet on the Road; Eric Bush Fundraiser; European Firms in Michigan; Namibian President's dinner; Flint Rotary lunch; J. Ryan Fundraiser; Welfare Reform press conference, October 24-30, 1995 (Box 124)
      - General Motors signing; China toast; African World Expo; Luncheon with President of Ghana, October 30-31, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Boy Scouts 85th Anniversary; Michigan Quality Leadership Award; National Education Goals Panel; International Investment Organization; Wayne County Domestic Violence Conference, November 1-16, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Commercial Club of Chicago, November 9, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Catholic Campaign for America Keynote "Be Not Afraid: Look the Adversary in the Eye,", November 18, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Republican Governors' Association; Genesee/Saginaw/Bay City/Midland GOP Fundraiser, November 20-27, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Welfare Reform Bill Signing, December 6, 1995 (Box 124)
      - Economic Club of Detroit, January 10, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: NRCC Challenger Fundraiser; Introduction of Newt Gingrich, January 16-24, 1996 (Box 124)
      - State of the State: "Advancing Michigan's Renaissance,", January 17, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Republican National Committee Meeting, San Diego, January 19, 196 (Box 124)
      - Michigan Press Association, January 24, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Republican Governors' Association -- America's Majority Dinner; Phillip Morris Acknowledgment; Michigan Society of Association Executives; New Partnerships Planning, February 5-12, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Michigan Farm Bureau Legislative Seminar; Great Lakes Games Press Conference; YPO/DPO Dinner; Senate Caucus Fundraiser, February 13-26, 1996 (Box 124)
      - House Ways & Means Testimony on Human Resources, February 20, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Conservative Political Action Committee (CPAC) Conference Awards Dinner (JME receives state leadership award), February 23, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Focus on the Family remarks: "It takes a Family,", March 1, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Florida Forum Club, March 8, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Detroit Diesel Investors' Day Dinner, March 11, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Randy (Duke) Cunningham Introduction, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Hillsdale Center for Constructive Alternatives: "Future of American Business,", March 13, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Holocaust Remembrance, April 16, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Detroit-Beijing Northwest Airlines Route; Rochester Area Prayer Breakfast; Tulip Time, Hol, May 1-15, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Republican House Dinner; Kalamazoo Lincoln Day Dinner; Jack Horton Fundraiser; Wayne Co. Republican Dinner; Joe Fitzsimmons Fundraiser; Iowa State Republican Party, May 9-30, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Bob Dole introduction, June 3, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Olympic Torch Presentation; 50th Ordination celebration for the Rev. Louis C. Cappo; George Kinsella fundraiser; Cabinet meeting, June 5-12, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Republican National Convention Outlook Talking points; Governor's Gala, June 17-25, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Auto Centennial, June 22, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: MSU Trustee Appointment; University of Michigan Media Union opening; Michigan School Report Card; Speed Limit bill signing; Macomb Community Bank; Camp Grayling Review, June 19-28, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Renaissance Zone bill signing; Intro Bob Dole for Max Fisher Award; Angela Hospice bill signing; Atoma International of America groundbreaking, Mac McClellan Breakfast; Ionia Free Fair Day, July 17-31, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Council of Great Lakes Governors Roundtable with Bob Dole, July 22, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Detroit Riverfront Acquisition, July 23, 1996 (Box 124)
      - "The Michigan Miracle: Model for the 21st Century" article for Imprimis (Hillsdale), August 1996 (Box 124)
      - Republican National Convention Education Segment, August 13, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Gov. Englers Remarks for Republican National Convention, August 12-13, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Republican Unity Events, August 7-19, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Republican State Convention, September 7, 1996 (Box 124)
      - "Looking into the Faces of Children," National Forum on Children and Violence Beverly Hills, California, September 11, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Hand-tools Institute Luncheon, Cleveland, Ohio, September 12, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Economic Club of Detroit Jack Kemp Introduction, September 13, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Economic Club of Detroit Bob Dole Introduction, September 24, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Michigan GOP Challengers' Event; Dennis LeMaitre event; Gary Woronchak event; Larry Julian event, September 17-24, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Novi Chamber of Commerce, September 20, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Judge Bill Murphy Press Conference, September 23, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Flint Economic Club, September 24, 1996 (Box 124)
      - US Senate Judiciary Committee Testimony: Role of US Department of Justice in Prison Litigation Reform, September 25, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Robin Hayes for Governor of North Carolina, September 25, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Bow Hunting Press Conference; Haworth Building dedication; Introduction May or Steve Goldsmith of Indianapolis for Governor of Indiana, September 26-30, 1996 (Box 124)
      - Driver's License Bill Signing, September 30, 1996 (Box 124)
      - CATA Study on Tax Cuts, September-October 1996 (Box 124)
      - Mary Matalin and James Carville Introduction, Fall 1996 (Box 124)
      - Remarks: Events for Pete Lund, Steve Rice, Ronna Romney, Gary Woronchak, Eric Bush, Christina Clark, Jim Ryan, Ed Nykiel, Pat Nowak, October 1-28, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: 75th Anniversary Michigan Department of Agriculture, Farewell to Dr. Guyer; Welfare press conference, 100,000 cases closed; Van Andel Arena dedication, October 2-8, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Illinois GOP appearances for Lee Daniels, IL Speaker; Congressman Harris Fawell, October 4-5, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Economic Club of Detroit, October 7, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Catholic Chamber "Governors' breakfast" Students' Question Time, October 7, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Ypsilanti Chamber of Commerce Breakfast; American Society of Newspaper Editors; Right to Life Dinner; Tax Cut Press Conference, October 15-25, 1996 (Box 125)
      - DeSana Fundraiser, October 24, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Dole Press Conference Remarks, October 28, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Susy Heintz event; Bob Dole rally, President Ford Introduction, Grand Rapids, November 1, 1996 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: M 25 Ribbon Cutting; Jewish National Fund Tree of Life Award; Welcome Republican Governors' Association to Grand Rapids, November 1-23, 1996 (Box 125)
      - "The Liberal Rout: Why Republicans Are Winning," article for Policy Review, November 1996 (Box 125)
      - Baker Institute, Rice University, Houston, November 12, 1996 (Box 125)
      - State Board of Education, December 12, 1996 (Box 125)
      - '95 Crime Statistics Michigan State Police Press Conference, December 11, 1996 (Box 125)
      - CEI Warren Brooks Dinner, Washington, DC or, 1996; 1997 (Box 125)
      - Criminal Justice Reform Agenda, January 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Jobs and Technology Message; Press Conference on lower unemployment; Family Independence Agency Appointment; Jewish Business Exchange; Jobs Commission Board; Michigan Press Association, January 20-24, 1997 (Box 125)
      - State of the State: "Our Families, Our Future,", January 28, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Michigan GOP Convention Keynote Address, February 1, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life, February 11, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Society of Automotive Engineers, Greater Detroit Chamber of Commerce Breakfast, February 26, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Michigan Senate GOP Dinner; Macomb County Lincoln Day; Muskegon County Lincoln Day; Wayne County Eisenhower Day; Berrien County Lincoln Day, March 3-22, 1997 (Box 125)
      - National Association of Business Economists' Washington Policy Seminar, March 5, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Greeting to President Clinton in Special Session of Michigan Legislature, March 6, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Michigan State University Agriculture Pavilion Dedication; Unemployment drop press conference; United Way of Southwest Michigan; Tourism Theme Press Conference; Investiture of Joan Young and Wendy Potts; Transportation Improvement announcement; Workforce Board, March 16-31, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Council on Competitiveness Annual Meeting, March 21, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Budget/Tax Cuts press conference; Grand Rapids Ford Presidential Museum; Cigarette Stamp press Conference; Crime Victims' Rights Vigil, April 14-22, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Build Michigan II: Repair, Reform and Responsibility, May 8, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Detroit Yacht Club Sendoff for Betty Appleby, May 7, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Drive Savings and Lawsuit Protection Plan, May 13, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Wayne State Law School Commencement; Automotive Hall of Fame grant presentation; Fr. William Cunningham Eulogy; Greater Detroit Chamber of Commerce, May 10-31, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Oakland Co. GOP Finance Meeting, May 12, 1997 (Box 125)
      - National Meeting of State Services Commissions, Mid, May 16, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Europe and USA Toward 2000 Florence, Italy, May 29, 1997, 1997-2000 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Upper Peninsula Children's Museum; Michigan Manufacturers Association; May unemployment Rate Drop press conference; George Romney Building dedication, June 2-19, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Lincoln Day in Alger, Delta, Dickenson, Menominee (Build Michigan); Governors' Gala, June 2-23, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Michigan Investment Seminar, New York City, June 10, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: University of Michigan Cancer and Geriatrics Center dedication; Michigan State University Ag Expo Breakfast; Site Consultants' Meeting, June 13-25, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Courtyards of Mackinaw, June 14, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Alfershausen Roundtable Germany, June 20, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Department of Natural Resources Press Conference, June 24, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: G. Mennen Williams Building dedication; I-75/Porter Street groundbreaking; 9th Street Bridge (Kalamazoo) completion; Blue Water Bridge, 2nd Span opening, July 1-12, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Troy Chamber of Commerce Pancakes and Politics; Grand Rapids Rotary; Michigan Association of Broadcasters Awards Dinner, July 16-25, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Republican National Committee remarks; Undated Talking points for Senate Hearing, July 18, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Build Michigan II press conferences: Southfield, Grand Lodge, Kalamazoo; Old St. Joseph County Courthouse rededication; Issues of the Week, August 1, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Upper Peninsula State Fair; Delta County Chamber; Supreme Court Taylor appointment; Oldsmobile Centennial; Michigan State Fair; Department of Natural Resources State Fair Exhibit, August 15-22, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Lake Michigan GOP Barbecue, Grand Haven; Senator Doug Carl Eulogy, August 20-21, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Proposal A Press Conference, September 3, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Remarks: Partnership for a Drug Free Michigan; Ottawa County Project Zero Success; C. Taylor investiture; Blue Ribbon Teachers, September 4-22, 1997 (Box 125)
      - "Road Fix Blitz"/Build Michigan II, on-site speeches, September 9-10, 1997 (Box 125)
      - Frederick Douglas Awards dinner, September 10, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Mackinac GOP Conference Keynote Address, September 20, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Durant Case Settlement, September 22, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Governor's Education Summit, Lansing, September 23, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Macomb County Economic Club; Lakes Area Chamber of Commerce, Milford; Ghafari G-Tech Anniversary; University of Michigan-Dearborn building dedication; Right to Life dinner, September 24-26, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Detroit Economic Club Career Preparation Press Conference, September 29, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: National Alliance for Business (NAB) "State of the Year" award; Jim Gilmore Fundraiser; Michigan Automobile Dealers Association (MADA) letter, September 30, 1997 (Box 126)
      - US House Testimony on Education/Workforce/Oversight & Investigations at Muskegon, October 2, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Domestic Violence Awareness Month Press Conference, October 2, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: 60th Anniversary of Michigan Chronicle, Lam Logan Tribute; Justice Dorothy Comstock Riley Tribute; Davidson Freeway Reopening; Cadillac Chamber breakfast; Student Questions, October 6-9, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: "Clean Corporate Citizen" Awards; Roney Superstar 10 Awards; Chaldean Federation of America; "Corrections Day" Testimony, October 10-16, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Southfield Town Hall: Education; Clarkson High School Visit; Smith Middle School, Troy; "Fatherhood is Forever" Kick-off; Foundation for Traditional Values banquet, October 17, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Pontiac Rotary 75th Anniversary; American Polish Coalition Republicans; Arab-American Chamber banquet: "Economic Development = One Potential Catalyst of Peace in Middle East,", October 18-19, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Royal Oak Chamber of Commerce Luncheon; William Whitbeck Investiture; Michigan State University Food Safety/Toxicology building dedications; 1997 Tourism Conference, October 20-27, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: "Project Zero" Kick-off, Greydale; Kent Co.; Manistee Co., October 20-28, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Michigan Elementary and Middle School Principals Association; Senior Nutrition 25th Anniversary; Tiger Stadium Groundbreaking; Urban Homestead/Hudson Institute; Michigan State Police 115th Trooper Recruit School Graduation, October 28-31, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Speechwriter Assignments, October 21-November 18, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Remarks: Gov. Christie Whitman Rally (NJ); Justice Dorothy Comstock Riley Retirement Dinner, November 1-3, 1997 (Box 126)
      - Sylvan Prometrics "Results 97" Conference, San Antonio, Texas (On education technology), November 7, 1997 (Box 126)
      - National Governors' Conference on Quality in Education, Dearborn, November 9, 1997 (Box 126)